English

AdLock Privacy Policy
=====================

last updated 21st of March 2023

AdLock collects Personal Data from the User (You) if it is necessary for delivery of services of AdLock listed on the adlock.com website (https://adlock.com). You may contact AdLock through email gdpr@adlock.com or within Contact Form on https://adlock.com/ at any time if you want to delete, change, transfer or perform any other actions with data, that belongs to You.

Please read this Privacy Policy (hereinafter the "Privacy Policy") carefully before using our website, applications or any other AdLock products or services.

The Privacy Policy provides description of information that we collect from the User and can use when rendering our services.

Information is collected in the minimum scope necessary to ensure functional capacity of our products.

For use of our website, application or any other AdLock product, your consent to the processing of your personal data is required.

Data Controller
---------------

AdLock is trade name fully owned and administrated by:

Hankuper, s. r. o.  
Address: Špitálska 53, 811 01 Bratislava, Slovenská republika  
Email: GDPR@AdLock.com  

Hankuper, s. r. o. is the Data Controller of all personal data collected by AdLock website, AdLock mobile applications for Android and iOS devices, and AdLock desktop applications for Windows and macOS.

Personal data collected by AdLock
---------------------------------

AdLock collects first name, second name, email address and phone number when you register in AdLock.

_Purpose of collection: communication with the user in order to provide service and promotional information._

AdLock may collect other information provided by Yourself through contact form, support ticket or in email when you contact AdLock.

_Purpose of collection: processing of the User’s requests, inquiries and claims._

AdLock also collects technical data which do not identify You by itself, but it shall be connected to your personal data after You have completed registration in AdLock.

_Technical data collection is necessary to provide stable work of AdLock on your device._

AdLock for Android collects the following data from your Android device:

* Application identifier (generated automatically for every User);
* Application version;
* Device name (which includes both device manufacturer name and device model name);
* IP address (allowing us to provide a better service to that specific country);
* Media Access Control address (MAC address);
* Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI);
* Device serial number;
* Display dimensions (allowing us to provide a better UI on your specific device);
* The main language chosen in the device’s settings (allowing us to provide UI in your language);
* Version of Android operating system used on the device;
* Crash reports. Crash reports are sent to us if AdLock unexpectedly shuts down while you’re using it. Those reports do not include your personal data. They provide us the chain of events (only parts of our code) before the shutdown that will help us to fix those issues in the following releases;
* Information about applications installed on Your device.

AdLock for Windows collects the following data from your Windows personal computer:

* Local directory address in which AdLock application was installed;
* Media Access Control address (MAC address);
* Serial number;
* Display dimensions (allowing us to provide a better UI on your specific device);
* The main language chosen in the device’s settings (allowing us to provide UI in your language);
* IP address (allowing us to provide a better service to that specific country);
* Version of Windows operating system installed on your personal computer:
* Information about hardware used in your personal computer’s configuration (such as bios details, video card details etc.)
* Crash reports. Crash reports are sent to us if AdLock unexpectedly shuts down while you’re using it. Those reports do not include your personal data. They provide us the chain of events (only parts of our code) before the shutdown that will help us to fix those issues in the following releases. You can find a file which stores each crash report that we received in a Temp folder on your computer. To open these reports and see exactly what data we're receiving from you:  
    Go to C:\\Users\\your\_user\_name\\AppData\\Local\\Temp\\Hankuper\\AdLock\\  
    View a report file in any text editor for example Notepad.

AdLock for Mac collects the following data from your Mac personal computer:

* Media Access Control address (MAC address);
* The version of macOS operating system installed on your personal computer;
* Model;
* IP address (allowing us to provide a better service to that specific country);
* Serial number;
* Display dimensions (allowing us to provide a better UI on your specific device);
* The main language chosen in the device’s settings (allowing us to provide UI in your language);
* Crash reports. Crash reports are sent to us if AdLock unexpectedly shuts down while you’re using it. Those reports do not include your personal data. They provide us the chain of events (only parts of our code) before the shutdown that will help us to fix those issues in the following releases.

AdLock for iOS collects the following data from your iOS device:

* Model;
* The version of iOS operating system installed on your device;
* IP address;
* Serial number.

AdLock Extension (Chrome) declares such permissions as:

* "Access data for all websites" : in order to make our product fully functional for your protection from ads.
* "Access to browser tabs" to get information about website you visit (website url, tab id, parent tab id). It allows to block annoying ad requests, get rid of ad images and hide empty blocks with special cosmetic and net rules.
* “Web navigation” permission allows extension watches tab changes and reacts to keep webpage clean from ads.

The AdLock extension gathers anonymous usage information including browser language, number of blocked ad requests, stores it on your local storage and doesn’t sell or share it with third parties. The AdLock extension also creates unique ID and anonymously assigns to each installation. This ID is stored on AdLock server until you uninstall the AdLock extension.

Processing of your Personal data by third parties
-------------------------------------------------

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow Data Controller to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Handling payments, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Location-based interactions, managing contacts and sending messages and Managing support and contact requests.

_Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data_

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

**• Analytics**

The services contained in this section enable Data Controller to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of the User behavior.

**Google Analytics (Google Inc.)**

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of AdLock, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

**Firebase Analytics (Google Inc.)**

Firebase Analytics is the analytics component of Firebase platform for mobile developers that provided by Google Inc. (“Google”).It's focused on app analytics and provides crash reporting and analysis.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy/)

**• Handling payments**

Payment processing services enable AdLock to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. AdLock has no any access to Your credit cards’ data or other payment data, this kind of data is processed on the side of payment processing services providers.

Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

Payment processing services provider (PayPro Global, Inc.)

Place of processing: Canada – [Privacy Policy](https://payproglobal.com/compliance-data-privacy/) – [Contact to Opt Out](https://payproglobal.com/data-protection/)

**• Hosting and backend infrastructure**

This type of service has the purpose of hosting data and files that enable AdLock to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of AdLock.

Data center’s company (Hetzner Online GmbH)

Place of processing: Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hetzner.com/rechtliches/datenschutz) – [Contact to Opt Out](https://www.hetzner.com/support-form)

**• Email marketing**

We may use Your email for promotional and infromational mailing through MailChimp software. You will have possibility to opt out using appropriate button in every mail You get from AdLock.

MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.

Personal Data collected: email address.

Place of processing: US

**• Geo service**

This type of service has the purpose of detecting the user's country by IP address. Using it we can check and adjust user experience and application accordingly.

Data center’s company (Apilayer Data Products Gmbh)

Place of processing: Austria – [Privacy Policy](https://www.ideracorp.com/Legal/APILayer/PrivacyStatement)

Methods of processing
---------------------

AdLock processes the Data of the Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by Data Controller. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

Place of processing
-------------------

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating office and in other places where the parties involved with the processing are located.

Retention time
--------------

We retain Personal Data for as long as necessary to continue providing you with these products and services, or until you revoke your consent to share this information.

YOUR RIGHTS
-----------

You have rights, at any time,

* to know whether Your Personal Data has been stored and consult the Data Controller to learn about its’ contents and origin;
* to verify Your Personal Data accuracy;
* to oppose Your Personal Data treatment for any and all legitimate reasons;
* to receive a downloadable copy of all the personal data on file within 30 days of request;
* to request removal of all data on file within 30 days of receipt of request.

**_

Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

All requests shall be processed in 30 days’ time frame.

_**

Safety
------

If you enable "Safe Browsing" option, AdLock application checks every website before you visit it. We use Update API technology for this purpose, and the information about the visited website is sent in form of hash prefixes. This does not allow us to determine which website is being visited.

When browsing security is enabled, AdLock periodically does a latency check for the list of browsing security servers; no information is sent in these requests, though.

We do not incorporate spyware or adware into our products and do not allow distributing any commercial notices to third parties by means of spyware (spyware is any software downloaded to or installed at the computer or device of the Internet user without actual consent that supports demonstration of commercial notices for the user).

This Privacy Policy applies to AdLock products only.

Cookies
-------

We use and allow using automatic methods such as cookies (small amounts of information containing a unique sequence of symbols sent to your browser or application from the website computers and kept on the hard drive of your computer or device).

The information collected and analysed by means of these methods includes without limitation personal information confirmed by you, IP address used to connect your computer or device with the Internet; e-mail; login and password of the personal account; type and version of the operating system, and computer or device platform.

We use software to assess and collect session data, including page standby time, loading errors, duration of visits at specific pages, information on interaction with the page (such as scrolling, clicking a mouse and mousing over elements) and methods used to go to other pages.

Data received from cookies are processed by means of different analysis tools and can be used to determine your geographic location, post code (by using your IP address and automatic geolocation methods) or to receive basic information on the computer, tablet or mobile telephone you use. We can also use these data internally or jointly with our partners to improve operation of AdLock products.

Geolocation data help us deliver content in the correct language, offer region or country-specific products and determine your local currency in case of a purchase. Cookies can help you enter by remembering the user account data (subject to the parameters you have selected in your account settings). Cookies can also be used to record contents of the cart and information on the user's registration. Cookies can help us determine your settings, in particular the language and currency, for further use.

**_

You may turn off cookies in your web browser.

_**

Provision of Information by Request of Court or Law Enforcement Authorities
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Information on the user received by us will be provided to court or another law enforcement authority in case respective request, order, warrant or another binding document is received.

Furthermore, you consent to and give us the right of use, disclosure and provision of your personal information for investigation and prevention of any illegal activities, fraud, potential threats and risks for human life and health.

Changes to this Privacy Policy
------------------------------

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time by giving notice to the Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using AdLock and can request that the Data Controller remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about the User.

Definitions and legal references
--------------------------------

**Personal Data** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person;

**Processing** means any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction;

**Data Controller** means the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data;

**AdLock** the software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected;

**Cookies** small piece of data stored in the User's device;

**Legal information Notice to European Users:** this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies. This privacy policy relates solely to AdLock.

Latest news
-----------

[

### 12 Best Free Solitaire Apps With No Ads for Android & iOS](https://adlock.com/blog/free-solitaire-apps-no-ads/)

[

### 26 Best Ad-Free Games for Android & iOS](https://adlock.com/blog/blog-free-mobile-games-no-ads/)

[

### The Best Christmas Ads That Touched Our Hearts](https://adlock.com/blog/best-christmas-ads/)

[

### How to Stop Automatic New Tabs Opening in Google Chrome](https://adlock.com/blog/how-to-stop-automatic-tabs-opening-in-google-chrome/)

[

### Ad Blocker Detected: How To Remove It?](https://adlock.com/blog/how-to-stop-ad-blocker-detection-on-websites/)

[

### Ad-Free Twitch: How to Block Annoying Ads](https://adlock.com/blog/how-to-block-twitch-ads/)

© adlock.com 2016 - 2024

Slovakia,  
Špitálska 53,  
811 01 Bratislava

Fill out the form and we will contact you shortly

Your name

Your email \*

Message \*

SubmitWe do not share your data with any third parties and use it only for communication with you

An error has occurred

Thank you! Data has been sent
